Razelle Ann Dela Cruz

Senior QA Analyst / Team Lead (Manual Testing)

Contact

San Rafael, Bulacan, Philippines

(+63)917 656 8400

razelleanndelacruz@gmail.com

https://radelacruz.github.io/portfolio/

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS
- Software Testing Life Cycle
- Software Development Life Cycle
 - Waterfall Model
 - V-shaped Model
 - Agile Model

Automotive System Testing

- Model-Based Design Testing
- Unit Testing of Embedded Software (C/C++)
 - Gray Box Testing
 - Coverage Testing

• Health Care System Testing

- Functional Testing
- Smoke Testing
- Regression Testing
- Manual Testing and Automated

(Tosca) Testing

- Defect Retest

• Banking System Testing

- Defect Retest
- System Integration Testing

SOFT SKILLS

- Attention to details
- Quality Control Circle
- Project Management, Project Leader

Summary

Software Quality Assurance Engineer with more than 10 years of experience in Software Testing and have experience in project management tasks. I have experienced working in a very challenging environment with high expectations of project quality and productivity.

Experience

SEVEN SEVEN GLOBAL SERVICES INC.

October 2021 - Present

Job Title: QA Analyst Team Lead (February 2022 – Present)

Perform testing activities for the Banking domain to confirm the correctness and functionality of the system.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Team Leader (February 2022 – Present)

- Create and send daily and weekly project status reports.
- Ensure good quality and timely delivery of project deliverables.
- Communicate and collaborate with developers, leaders and governance team regarding project updates.
- Review and submit team member's payroll
- Participate in daily and weekly meetings
- Create standard documents and other test completion reports.

Senior Test Analyst (October 2021 – February 2022)

- Test data preparation, setting up of user roles and responsibilities
- Analyze, create detailed test plans and cases, and perform peer reviews.
- Log and report all issues/defects encountered.
- Assist team leader in assigning daily tasks and creating and sending project status reports.
- Ensure good quality and timely delivery of project deliverables.

TOOLS

- Version Control System: SVN, Git
- **Testing Tool:** Eclipse IDE, Tricentis TOSCA, Coverage Master WinAMS
- Reports: MS Office, SharePoint, MvWizzard
- **Defect Management:** HP Application Lifecycle Management (ALM), Microsoft Test Manager (MTM), JIRA

TRAINING

- Basic Tricentis TOSCA Automation Training
- Basic C/C++ Training
- Basic Matlab Design Training
- Quality Control Circle
- Project Leader Training
- Coverage Master WinAMS
- Basic Japanese Language Training

CERTIFICATION

- Tricentis Tosca Automation Specialist Level 1
- Tricentis Tosca Automation Specialist Level 2
- Agila Gantimpala Award
- Tuitt Coding Bootcamp Certification
- Best in Quality (Person in Charge)
- Most Improved DR2 (Technical Reviewer)
- Best Reviewer (Technical Reviewer)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering (BSECE)

Bulacan State University (BulSU) Malolos, Bulacan S.Y. 2006-2011

THREE MONTHS INTENSIVE TRAINING

Tuitt Coding Bootcamp Metro Manila, PH November 2018 – February 2019

ACCENTURE INC.

June 2019 - October 2021

Job Title: Test Engineering Team Lead (June 2021 – October 2021)

Perform testing activities for Medicare Enrollment Applications and Medical Claims to confirm the correctness and functionality of the system.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Team Leader (June 2021 - October 2021)

- Provide project estimates, team capacity, and status reports.
- Ensure good quality and timely delivery of project deliverables.
- Directly communicate and collaborate with offshore leaders, onshore leaders, and business leaders.
- Create and send members daily tasks and facilitate daily huddles.
- Review and submit team member's payroll.
- Participate in weekly leaders' meetings, deliberations for performance appraisal, and monthly and quarterly Gantimpala Awards.
- Review and send the Test Support team's weekly status report, team capacity, and planned time offset. (7 subteam).

Senior Test Analyst/Sub-group Leader (June 2019 – May 2021)

- Analyze, create detailed test plans and test cases, and perform peer reviews. Perform regression testing when functionality testing is complete.
- Assist team leader in providing project estimates, team capacity, and status reports.

DENSO TEN SOLUTIONS PHILIPPINES CORPORATION

January 2012 - August 2018

Job Title: Software QA Engineer (January 2012 – August 2018)

Perform software testing activities for automotive electronics - Electronic Control Unit (ECU) source code.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Project Leader (March 2017 - March 2018)

- In charge of the overall progress monitoring including the productivity and quality of the projects.
- Responsible for checking the testing procedures and working closely with the Audit team to ensure testing standards are met.

Sub-group Leader (March 2016 – August 2018)

- Maximize the team members' capabilities, skills, and capacity while guiding and teaching them.

Senior Technical Reviewer (August 2014 – August 2018)

 Ensure project quality by reviewing the tester's output and ensuring that all items are correctly inspected.

Software Tester (January 2012 – May 2017)

 Analyze, create test plans and test cases, and execute the Unit Testing.